snbforums.com 2018-10-13

# SNBForums Privacy Policy | SmallNetBuilder Forums

Dismiss Notice

****

**Welcome To SNBForums**

SNBForums is a community for anyone who wants to learn about or discuss the latest in wireless routers, network storage and the ins and outs of building and maintaining a small network.

If you'd like to post a question, simply [register](http://www.snbforums.com/login/) and have at it!

While you're at it, please check out [SmallNetBuilder](http://www.smallnetbuilder.com/) for product reviews and our famous [Router Charts](http://www.smallnetbuilder.com/tools/charts/router/view), [ Ranker](http://www.smallnetbuilder.com/tools/rankers/router/view) and plenty more!

###### Updated 30 May 2018

SNBForums (hereinafter referred to as "SNBF" or "We") is committed to ensuring the privacy of its readers and registered members and wants you to fully understand our terms and conditions This privacy statement describes how any personal, and anonymous, information is collected and managed and how you can request changes to any sharing of this information that may occur.

### Statistical Reports and Analytics

SNBF's servers automatically recognize a visitor's IP address and domain name. These items do not reveal any personal information about the visitor. The information is used solely to compile statistics that enable us to examine page impression levels and numbers of unique users visiting our Web sites. This information helps us to understand the areas of our sites that people visit in order to deliver more effective content.

We use Google Analytics to learn more about how the site is used and to improve our content. For more information about Google's use of information, [please see their disclosure here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). Certain information such as your browser, and your IP address may be sent to Google Analytics, but this information is always anonymized so that we don’t know which specific visitors are associated with what browser. We do not have access to any IP information in Google Analytics. 

Google Analytics may use several cookies, including cookies stored for very long periods, in order to determine if you have visited the site before. But Google Analytics never associates any user-identifiable information with your visit. So we may know many people visit a particular page, but we won’t know specifically who read it. To opt out of being counted in Google Analytics, [you can install this browser add on made by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). 

### Essential Cookies

Like most other websites, SNBF uses cookies. Cookies are small data files that some websites write to your device's local storage when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you've visited. Cookies do not tell us who you are unless you've specifically given us personally identifiable information. A cookie can't read data off your hard drive or read cookie files created by other sites.

Certain operations and features on SNBF may require the use of cookies and/or the propagation of session information to facilitate the visitor's experience on SNBF. These cookies are used for the sole purpose of storing and maintaining user-submitted site preferences. SNBF does not intentionally use these cookies to "track" users. We will not provide any individually identifying information from cookies originating at SmallNetBuilder.com to any third party, including advertisers and sponsors. 

Because these cookies do not contain personal information, are used only for critical or non-trivial operations and can not be replaced with reasonable alternatives, we send these cookies under Legitimate Interest basis and do not request consent from EU users for these cookies. If you wish to block these or other cookies, most web browsers provide settings to control cookie use.

Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but allow you to modify security settings so you can approve or reject cookies on a case-by-case basis.

### Pixel Tags

SNBF may also use pixel tags, also known as beacons, web bugs or clear gifs, to improve our understanding of site traffic, visitor behavior, and response to promotional campaigns, as a supplement to our server logs and other methods of traffic and response measurement. Pixel tags are sometimes used in conjunction with small Javascript-based applications, also for the purpose of traffic measurement. We may also implement pixel tags provided by other companies, for the same purpose.

### Online Ad Serving

Our primary advertising partner is Google. [Go to this page for information on how Google uses information from sites or apps that use its services](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). You can control Ad Personalisation by Google Ads and Google products by visiting the [Google Ad Settings page](https://adssettings.google.com/). 

We also directly serve some ads via our ad partner Velum Media. These ads use no cookies and anonymize each user's IP address. So no personalization or user tracking is done.

### Affiliates

SNBF earns revenue as an Amazon Affiliate. We are paid a commission if you purchase a product or service via any link on SNBF that sends you to Amazon. Amazon provides SNBF information about products purchased, but never in a form that links purchases and users. Please consult [Amazon's Privacy Notice](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496) for information on how Amazon uses your information and your options for controlling that information.

### Email Announcements

We may occasionally send you emails announcing new SNBF site features and initiatives. If you do not wish to receive messages of this nature from SNBF, please use the unsubscribe link provided in the email. Finally, if we run a contest or promotion, we may ask you for your full name and address in order to properly manage the promotion contests and to deliver notification to winners. We do not share this information with third parties without user consent.

Digest and thread/post email notices are controlled in your user account settings.

### Necessary Disclosure

The necessary disclosure of any of the above information to third parties will be governed by the following principles:

1\. Where SNBF is required to do so by law and any order of the court.  
2\. Where it is necessary to identify anyone who may be violating the rights of others or the law in general.  
3\. Where SNBF intends to co-operate with the investigation of any alleged unlawful activities without being required to by virtue of any court order or other legal requirement.  
4\. Where it is necessary to protect the rights of SNBF. 

### Surveys

Occasionally, SNBF conducts user surveys to better understand the needs of our audience in order to improve our features. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our advertisers and partners. We never share any information about specific individuals with any third party without the user's consent.

### Security

We use all reasonable precautions to securely maintain all information given to us by our registered members and we are not responsible for any breach of the reasonable security measures installed to protect the said information. We are not responsible for the private policies of any site linked to, or from, SNBF.

### Opt Out Policy

SNBF gives users options whenever necessary, and practical. Such choices include: Opting not to receive our electronic messages, opting not to provide certain optional personal information when registering for an account.

### Transfer of Information

SNBF reserves the right to transfer any information accumulated as described above in the event of the sale of part or all of SNBF assets and/or stock. By visiting our Web sites you consent to the collection and use of information in the manner herein described.

### Contacting SNBF

You may contact us using the [Contact Us link](https://www.snbforums.com/misc/contact) at the bottom of each page.

### Privacy Policy Changes

This Privacy Policy may be modified from time to time. Any modifications to our Privacy Policy will be reflected on this page. If there is a significant change, we will indicate it on our sites and provide a link to the new policy.
